<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE book
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"  >
<book lang="en">
  <bookinfo>
	<title><inlinegraphic fileref="QSPics/logo.png"/>Contribution Managers Guide </title>
    	<corpauthor>CERN</corpauthor>
  </bookinfo>

<chapter id='contIntro'>
  	<title>Contribution Managers Guide</title>
	<sect1 id='contmgrintro'>
      	<title>Contribution Manager</title>
	      	<para>
			Being a Contribution Mananager you are responsible for managing the information in your contribution.
			Your are given contribution management access by either the Conference Manager, Session Manager, the existing Contribution Manager and possibly the Session Co-ordinator.
			</para>
			<para> 
			You can access your contribution by selecting 'timetable' from the left hand menu and finding your contribution if you are the manager of
			that contribution you will see a small red pen in the top right corner <inlinegraphic fileref="QSPics/pen.png"/> this will take
			you to your contribution management area.
			</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id='contmg'>
		<title>Contribution Management </title>
		<para>
			Once in the contribution management area you can start managing your contribution using the following tabs. 
		</para>
		<note><para>This is just a quick start guide for contribution management, for an indepth explanation please see "Contributions" in the Indico User Guide, section 2.4.3.1</para></note>
		<sect2 id='cmgmain'>
			<title>Main Tab</title>
			<para>
				The main tab contains all the data about the contribution itself.			
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/contco.png"/>		      	
			<para>
				Any information, material and people within this main tab apply to the contribution in general.
			</para>			
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='cmgsub'>
			<title>Sub Contribution Tab</title>
			<para>
				The sub contribution tab allows you to add and remove sub contributions.			
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/subcont.png"/>		      	
			<para>
				Clicking on the title of a sub contribution will take you into its management area.
			</para>			
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='cmgac'>
			<title>Access Control Tab</title>
			<para>
				The access control tab allows you to add other contribution managers and to give permission for users to submit material for 
				your contribution.			
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/contac.png"/>		      			
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='cmgarc'>
			<title>Archiving Tab</title>
			<para>
				The archiving tab allows you to see the achiving status of the contribution.			
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/contarch.png"/>		      				
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='cmgtool'>
			<title>Tools Tab</title>
			<para>
				The tools tab allows you to delete the contribution, move the contribution and write minutes for the contribution.			
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/conttool.png"/>		      				
		</sect2>
	</sect1>

</chapter>
</book>