<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE glossary
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"  >
<glossary><title><inlinegraphic fileref="QSPics/logo.png"/>Indico Glossary </title>


<glossdiv><title>A</title>

    <glossentry id ="abp"><glossterm>Absolutely Public</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>The state in which a resource is public, regardless of the status that is inherited from the parent resource.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
	<glossentry id ="ab"><glossterm>Abstract</glossterm>
	<glossdef><para>Ideas or summary of a presentation/contribution, often assigned to a track. Once accepted becomes a contribution.</para>
	</glossdef>
	</glossentry>
    
    <glossentry id ="acc"><glossterm>Account</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A register, associated with a user, and that enables him/her to authenticate his/her identity. Indico supports local accounts (no longer used at CERN) and NICE accounts (centrally registered at CERN, and authenticated through SSO).</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
    <glossentry id ="av"><glossterm>Avatar</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>An "Avatar" is a representation of a user in the Indico database. It usually contains all the user's personal info (that is extracted from the NICE database the first time the user logs into Indico). These data can be explicitly modified by the user. An Avatar is normally associated with one or more accounts.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
        

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv>

    <title>B</title>

    <glossentry id ="br"><glossterm>Break</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A pause in the schedule of a meeting/conference. Breaks can be placed inside sessions/slots or at the top level.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
        

</glossdiv>


<glossdiv><title>C</title>

    <glossentry id ="cat"><glossterm>Category</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A container for events. Categories can contain either other categories (sub-categories), or events, never both at the same time. The category hierarchy of Indico resembles a tree where categories that contain events are the "leaves".</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
    <glossentry id ="clon"><glossterm>Clone</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>Cloning a meeting means replicating it (with the exact same information) on a diferent date. This is normally useful for series of meetings whose participans and/or contents don't change significantly.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

    <glossentry id ="conf"><glossterm>Conference</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>The most complex kind of event, containing the same as a meeting, plus support for registration, abstract management, and other features that are specific to this kind of event.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

	<glossentry id ="cont"><glossterm>Contribution</glossterm>
	<glossdef><para>Usually a presentation taking place within a session or slot.</para>
	</glossdef>
	</glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv><title>E</title>

    <glossentry id ="eva"><glossterm>Evaluation</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A poll, that is conducted normally after an event takes place, so that the organizer can gather feedback about it. It can be applied to any event, and the results can be exported as stylesheets.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

    <glossentry id ="eve"><glossterm>Event</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>An event is either a Lecture, Meeting or Conference.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

</glossdiv>


<glossdiv><title>F</title>

    <glossentry id ="file"><glossterm>File</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>In the context of Indico, this is a resource that links to a physical file, contained in Indico's "archive". Files are stored inside materials.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv><title>L</title>

    <glossentry id ="lect"><glossterm>Lecture</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A presentation, normally done by one or more speakers. It doesn't contain any "substructures" such as contributions.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

    <glossentry id ="link"><glossterm>Link</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>In the context of Indico, a <em>Link</em> is a resource that links to some other resource on the Web, specified by a URL. Links exist inside materials.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv><title>M</title>

    <glossentry id ="mat"><glossterm>Material</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A <em>Material</em> is a container for <em>Files</em> and <em>Links</em>, it groups resources of the same nature (i.e. slides, documents, drawings...). Materials can be attached to Categories (quite rare), Events, Sessions, Contributions and Subcontributions.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

    <glossentry id ="meet"><glossterm>Meeting</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A kind of event that implies some degree of participation from  different participants, over different topics (<em>Contributions</em>). Contributions can be placed into <em>Sessions</em>, for better organization. Slots can also be used, but they are disabled by default.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
    <glossentry id ="min"><glossterm>Minutes</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para><em>Minutes</em> are annotations produced by participans in a meeting. They can be associated with Meetings, Sessions, Contributions and Subcontributions.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv><title>P</title>

    <glossentry id ="priv"><glossterm>Private</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A status in which a resource cannot be accessed by users that do not accomplish certain criteria (i.e. being in a list, or coming from a specific IP domain...).</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

    <glossentry id ="privh"><glossterm>Private by Inheritance</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A status in which an resource is private just because its parent resource was set as private (either by inheritance, or explicitly).</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
    <glossentry id ="pub"><glossterm>Public</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A status in which a resource is publicly accessible, with no constraints. This status can be overriden, if the parent resource is set as private (see <strong>Private by Inheritance</strong>).</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv><title>R</title>

    <glossentry id ="res"><glossterm>Resource</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>In the context of this document, a <em>Resource</em> is a category, event (lecture, meeting or conference), session, contribution, subcontribution, material, link or file. It is basically any information-bearing object in Indico's domain.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>
    
</glossdiv>
    
<glossdiv><title>S</title>

	<glossentry id ="sess"><glossterm>Session</glossterm>
	<glossdef><para>A time slot to help organise your conference timetable. Can contain slots, contributions and breaks.</para>
	</glossdef>
	</glossentry>

	<glossentry id ="slot"><glossterm>Slot</glossterm>
	<glossdef><para>A session can be split into slots, can be used when the session happens over more than one period of time. Can contain contributions and breaks.</para>
	</glossdef>
	</glossentry>
    
    <glossentry id ="sub"><glossterm>Subcontribution</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>A subdivision of a contribution.</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv><title>T</title>

	<glossentry id ="track"><glossterm>Track</glossterm>
	<glossdef><para>Often topics or areas in which to start organising your conference. Can contain abstracts and contributions.</para>
	</glossdef>
	</glossentry>

</glossdiv>

<glossdiv><title>V</title>

    <glossentry id ="vis"><glossterm>Visibility</glossterm>
    <glossdef><para>In the context of Indico, <em>Visibility</em> usually refers to the extent to which an event can be seen in the event overview page. This attribute sets whether the event can be seen as belonging to the top level class (and all those below), to none of them (invisible), or to one of the intermediate classes (and all those below).</para>
    </glossdef>
    </glossentry>

</glossdiv>


</glossary>