<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE book
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"  >
<book lang="en">
  <bookinfo>
	<title><inlinegraphic fileref="QSPics/logo.png"/>Session Manager's Guide </title>
    	<corpauthor>CERN</corpauthor>
  </bookinfo>

<chapter id='Intro'>
  	<title>Session Manager Guide</title>
<sect1 id='sessmgintro'>
      	<title>Session Manager</title>
	      	<para>
			Being a Session Manager you have full control of your session. However your conference manager may request you not to edit some
			parts of the session. You are given the session manager rights by your conference manager.		
			</para>
			<para> 
			To access the management area of your session, use the Timetable option on the left menu and click on your session's title,
			if you have been assigned as the session manager you will see a small red pen icon in the top right <inlinegraphic fileref="QSPics/pen.png"/>
			this will take you to your session.
			</para>
			
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id='sessmg'>
		<title>Session Management </title>
		<para>
			Once in the session management area you can start managing your session using the following tabs. 
		</para>
		<note><para>This is just a quick start guide for session management, for an indepth explanation please see "Session Management" in the Indico User Guide, section 2.4.5.4</para></note>

		<sect2 id='smgmain'>
			<title>Main Tab</title>
			<para>
				The main tab contains all the data about the session itself			
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/sessmain.png"/>		      	
			<para>
				Any information, material and people within this main tab apply to the entire session in general.
			</para>			
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='smgcontrib'>
			<title>Contributions Tab</title>
			<para>
				The contribution tab gives a list of all the contributions associated with your session.		
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/sesscontrib.png"/>		      	
			<para>
				Contributions need to be imported into your session before you can schedule them. By clicking on the contribution name
				you can then enter the modification area of that contribution.
			</para>			
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='smgtt'>
			<title>Timetable Tab</title>
			<para>
				The timetable tab lets you arrange the scheduling for your session, you can add/edit/delete slots organise when your
				contributions are going to take place and include breaks within your session.		
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/sesstt.png"/>		      	
			<para>
				To change the start times of each entry use the small red pen to the left of the entry's details.
			</para>			
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='smgac'>
			<title>Access Control Tab</title>
			<para>
				The Access Control tab is the area in which you can set access rights for your session. Please check with your conference manager
				before changing anything in here as they may wish to set all the access rights themselves.	
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/sessac.png"/>		      	
			<para>
				You can assign users the rights to be session co-ordinators or to be managers alongside yourself, a co-ordinator can 
				schedule contributions and breaks, they can only change slots if they conference manager has given them that right. A session
				co-ordinator cannot change details of the session itself.
				
			</para>			
		</sect2>
	
		<sect2 id='smgtools'>
			<title>Tools Tab</title>
			<para>
				The Tools tab allows you to delete the session and to write minutes for the session.
			</para>
		
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='smgcomm'>
			<title>Comments Tab</title>
			<para>
				The Comments tab stores any comments about your session you can view this comment but only the conference manager can
				modify the comments.	
			</para>
				<graphic fileref="QSPics/sesscom.png"/>   	
		
		</sect2>



			
	</sect1>


</chapter>
</book>
