<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE book
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"  >
<book lang="en">
  <bookinfo>
	<title><inlinegraphic fileref="QSPics/logo.png"/>Session Co-ordinator's Guide </title>
    	<corpauthor>CERN</corpauthor>
  </bookinfo>

<chapter id='Intro'>
  	<title>Session Co-ordinators Guide</title>
	<sect1 id='sesscointro'>
      	<title>Session Co-Ordinator</title>
	      	<para>
			Being a Session Co-Ordinator you are responsible for scheduling contributions and breaks within your session.
			These contributions need to be imported by the session manager or conference manager before you can add them to your session.
			</para>
			<para> 
			You are given this co-ordinator access by either the Session Manager or the Conference Manager.
			The Conference Manager sets the level of modification rights for all of the session co-ordinators. 
			You can access your session by selecting 'my session' from the left hand menu.
			</para>
			<graphic fileref="QSPics/mysess.png"/>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id='sessco'>
		<title>Session Co-ordination </title>
		<para>
			There are three levels of co-ordination modification that the Conference Manager can give to session co-ordinators.			
		</para>
		<para>
				If you do not have access or the rights to any part within your session you will be presented with this page:
			</para>
			<graphic fileref="QSPics/nomod.png"/>

		<sect2 id='basic'>
			<title>Basic Rights</title>
			<para>
				All Session Co-ordinators can:			
			</para>
		      	<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					Manage the timetable with restrictions - adding contributions, creating breaks, reschedule contributions and breaks. 					
				</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					View contribution list (cannot modify contributions) 
				</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					View the sessions' main information (cannot modify) 
				</para>
				</listitem>
	
				<listitem>
				<para>
					View comments from the conference manager (cannot modify) 
				</para>
				</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>

			<para>
				Your co-ordination will mainly take place within the Timetable tab of your session:
			</para>
			<graphic fileref="QSPics/basicco.png"/>
		</sect2>
		<sect2 id='contmod'>
			<title>Contribution Modification Rights</title>
			<para>
				If the conference manager has allowed contribution modification rights you can:			
			</para>
		      	<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					Modify the main data of the contribution.
				</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					Set the access controls for the contribution - i.e. give submission rights to presenters or allow others to manage the contribution.					
				</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					Add / remove sub contributions.					
				</para>
				</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			<para>To modify the contribution click on it's name from either the timetable or the contribution list.</para>
			<para>The contribution management area (For a more detailed explanation please see "Contribution" in the Indico User Guide 2.4.3.1):</para>
			<graphic fileref="QSPics/contco.png"/>
		</sect2>
			<sect2 id='ttmod'>
			<title>Unrestricted Timetable Management</title>
			<para>
				If the conference manager has allowed unrestricted timetable management rights you can:			
			</para>
		      	<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					Add contributions and breaks, reschedule contributions and breaks as before					
				</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				<para>
					Add, Edit and Delete slots				
				</para>
				</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			<para>
			The timetable management area will be the same as it was with the basic rights with the options to manage the slots:
			</para>
			<graphic fileref="QSPics/ttco.png"/>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>

</chapter>
</book>
