<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<!DOCTYPE book
  PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.2//EN"  >
<book lang="en">
  <bookinfo>
   	<title><inlinegraphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/logo.png"/>Indico Administrator's User Guide</title>
    	<corpauthor>CERN</corpauthor>

  </bookinfo>

<chapter id='start'>
  	<title>Starting with Indico</title>
	<sect1 id='createadminaccount'>
      		<title>Creating an Administration Account</title>
	      	<para>After installation the first screen presented to you will be:</para>
	      	<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/start1.png"/>
		<para>
			First thing needed is to create an administrator account by clicking on login. Administrators will have access and modification
			rights to all categories and events. You will be presented with a Log In screen and with an option to create an account.
			A form will need to be filled in with your user details. Once this is complete an email will be sent to you with a link to activate
			your account, once activated you will then be able to login and will be redirected to the administration area <link linkend=
			"admin">(See Administration Area)</link>.

		</para>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/start2.png"/>
		<para>
			From here you need to add your account to the administrator list, to do this click on 'add' under the title of 'Administrator List'
			and use the user search to find and select your account. You will then be an administrator and can start using all the features of
			Indico. Without an Administrator account anybody can access and change all parts of Indico leaving it exposed without any access control.
		</para>
		<para>
			Users can create their own accounts to use Indico in which you can modify, delete and add extra logins manually. You are also able to
			create new accounts and assign users to be administrators or organise users into groups <link linkend=
			"admin">(See Administration Area)</link>
		</para>
       </sect1>

	<sect1 id='acccreatebyuser'>
		<title>Accounts Created by a User</title>
		<para>
			When a new user wants to create an account, they can do so by clicking on 'login' in the top right hand corner of Indico.
			From here they can choose to create an account. A form will be presented that needs to be filled in with the user's details.
			Once submitted an email will be sent to the user.
		</para>


		<sect2 id='activateuseacc'>
			<title>Activating a User Created Account</title>
			<para>
				A user needs to activate their account by using the link that they are sent in an email after they apply for a new account.
				If the account is not activated the user cannot log in.
			</para>
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='retforgpswd'>
			<title>Retrieving a Forgotten Password</title>
			<para>
				If a user needs to retrieve their password, they can use the login screen and the forgotten password option; the user will
				be sent their password by email to the address registered with that account.
			</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>
</chapter>

<chapter id='admin'>
	<title>Administration Area</title>
	<para>
		The Administration Area controls the whole of Indico, anything you modify or add from here can be used throughout the whole program.
		From here you can change general information about your version of Indico, manually add, activate and modify accounts, add more than one
		login for a user, delete addition logins and you can assign users to groups You can also define domains for use with Access Control throughout
		Indico and you have control of any maintenance.
	</para>
	<sect1 id='adminmain'>
		<title>Main</title>
		<para>
			From the Main tab in the administration area, you are able to modify the system title, the organisation, the support email and address.
			You can also add or remove users to that administration list; this means they have full administration access throughout Indico.
		</para>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin1.png"/>
		<para>
			The Support email address you add in the General System Information will appear as the overall general support contact this will appear
			at the bottom of all the Display Areas:
		</para>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin2.png"/>
		<para>
			However if a problem occurs within the program and an error report needs to be sent this will be sent to the developers not to this
			support email.
		</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id='adminusers'>
		<title>Users</title>
		<para>
			From the User option in the Tools Menu you can control and modify any of the user accounts.
		</para>

		<sect2 id='manucreauser'>
			<title>Manually Creating a User</title>
			<para>
				To manually create a new account use the 'new user' option in the Tools menu. You will be presented with the same form to fill
				in as a user creating their own account, fill in and submit this form to create the account. You will still need to activate
				the account.
			</para>
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='usersearch'>
			<title>Searching for Users</title>
			<para>
				You can search for a user by their surname, first name, email address or organisation.If you are not sure of the full details you can 				enter the first few letters and it will show all the users that match your search. The Search filter is found by clicking on 'Users' 				in the Tools menu.
			</para>
		</sect2>


		<sect2 id='manuactacc'>
			<title>Manually Activating an Account </title>
			<para>
				To Activate an account from within the administration area,  go to the 'Users' option in the Tools Menu and search for the
				user's account using the filter,  then select the account you wish to activate, this will take you to the user's details:
			</para>
			<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin3.png"/>
			<para>
				If an account is not already activated its status will be 'not confirmed' click the button next to the status in order to
				activate the account. The account status will then be changed to 'activated' the user for that account will now be able to log in.
			</para>
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='modifuseacc'>
			<title>Modifying a User's Account</title>
			<para>
				From the Users Details screen above you have the option to modify the users' details from here you are able to modify the users
				affiliation, email address, postal address, telephone number and fax number.
			</para>
		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='creataddlogin'>
			<title>Creating Additional Logins for a User</title>
			<para>
				A user may have more than one login (username and password) on their account, this can be useful if a user has certain access
				rights with one login but not with another, they can then choose which login to use when using Indico.
			</para>
			<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin4.png"/>
			<para>
				To create a new login account for a user, use the 'create a new account' option this will take you to a screen where you can
				enter a new username and password.	Once the new account is added it will show in the User Details screen as above
			</para>

		</sect2>

		<sect2 id='deletaddlogin'>
			<title>Deleting Additional Logins</title>
			<para>
				To delete any additional account logins select the accounts for that user that you wish to delete and use the
				'delete selected accounts' option from the User Details screen above. A user must have one login account however.
			</para>
		</sect2>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id='groups'>
		<title>Groups</title>
		<para>
			You can use the groups section to categorise users if you wish. You may want to use this feature to help with Access Control
			for example if you have more than one user that you would like to manage an Event you could make a group of Managers for each
			event and then assign each set to an Event as apposed to adding each individual user.
		</para>
		<para>
			To create a new group use the 'new group' feature in the Tools menu . You will be asked for a group name and a description.
		</para>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin5.png"/>
		<para>
			You can then start to add or remove users to the group.
		</para>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin6.png"/>
		<para>
			You can assign a group of users the same was as you can individual users to Access Control. Once your
			group(s) are created you can use the 'Groups' option to find a particular group to continue adding and removing users or to modify
			the group details.
		</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id='domains'>
		<title>Domains</title>
		<para>
			You can add sets of IP address called Domains to be used in Access Control. To add a new domain use the
			'new domain' option in the Tools menu.
		</para>
		<para>
			You can then enter a name, description and the IP addresses you which to use in this domain:
		</para>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin7.png"/>
		<para>
			Any domains you create can be shown from the 'Domains' option in the menu, you can search for the domain name you want to look
			at and you will be shown the details of that Domain.
		</para>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin8.png"/>
		<para>
			From here you can also modify the domain.
		</para>
	</sect1>

	<sect1 id='maintenance'>
		<title>Maintenance</title>
		<para>
			The maintenance area is accessible from the 'Maintenance' option in the menu, from here you are able to:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
			<para>
				View the amount of Temporary files being used by Indico, Indico creates temporary files internally for example when a user submits a 				file or when creating a dvd, etc. These temporary files are stored until you delete them from here.
			</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			<para>
				Pack the Database, Indico periodically backs up your database and stores the older versions you can choose to remove older versions 				to save memory by using the 'pack' option, this will keep the current version of the database.
			</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
			<para>
				Delete Websessions, the database stores temporary information for the period in which an end user is navigating Indico for example 				whether they have chosen to have the menu in Display view opened or closed these periods are known as websessions. Websessions are 				stored in the database until you choose to delete them from here.
			</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<graphic fileref="AdminUserGuidePics/admin9.png"/>
		<para>
			You will be asked to confirm the deletion of temporary files and web sessions as well as when 'packing' the database.
		</para>

	</sect1>

</chapter>
</book>
